

Profile

Well-qualified Full Stack Developer with four years of experience, familiar with wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. Handles any part of process with ease. Four years of experience in frameworks like Django with Python, and libraries such as React JS with JavaScript. Experience with AWS. Looking for an entry-level position at a great company to be a hard-working asset to any team, to learn, grow and develop long-term.

Employment History

Senior Developer at Octobot, Montevideo, Uruguay

July 2019 — Present

- Planned, developed, tested, deployed over Kubernetes and AWS, and maintained web applications. Always developing with the Django & React JS stack. Some projects with Kafka.
- Provided effective troubleshooting and remediation for web applications.
- · Worked well independently and within a team setting.
- Managed a full-stack development for several USA companies, being in permanent contact with the different clients.
- Followed policies and procedures related to SCRUM methodology.
- Evaluated and became knowledgeable in new standards, technologies, and trends in web development.
- Regularly attend various DevOps meetups.
- Consulted with engineering team members to determine system loads and develop improvement plans.
- Coordinated with other teammates to evaluate and improve features to be developed.

Project Director / Senior Developer at traceit, Montevideo

January 2023 — Present

- Traceit is a COT (Customer-Oriented Traceability) system focused on the fruit and vegetable trade. Through a friendly interface, the producer declares and certifies the relevant events of his harvest, so that the final consumer can then read and evaluate them in the market. You can find the app in https://app.traceit.io.
- As the lead developer for the TraceIt project, I spearheaded the creation and implementation of a web application. Leveraging my expertise in React for the frontend and Django for the backend, I ensured seamless user experiences and robust functionality.
- Additionally, I orchestrated the deployment of the service using a range of AWS services, including EC2, RDS, and S3, optimizing performance and scalability.

Details

+59899596002

osmunogue@gmail.com

Links

LinkedIn

Skills

Python

Django

Django REST Framework

React

JavaScript

TypeScript

AWS

SQL

Docker

Git

Agile Methodologies, SCRUM

Kafka

OpenID Connect

Languages

Spanish

English

 This project not only honed my technical skills but also highlighted my ability to drive end-to-end development, from concept to deployment, showcasing my proficiency in full-stack development and AWS infrastructure management.

Education

Computer engineer, Universidad de la República, Montevideo, Uruguay

March 2016 — July 2022

Licenses and Certifications

Systems Analyst, Universidad de la República July 2019

First Certificate in English, Cambridge English Exams Cadiz

December 2016